{"tossups": [{"question": "Under Ulysses S. Grant, John Maynard Woodworth was the first holder of this position. While Thomas Parran held this position, one of his divisions controversially conducted an experiment at Tuskegee University to test African-Americans with syphilis treatments. C. Everett Coop sent out AIDS information documents to all U.S. households while holding this cabinet level position that holds a 3-star rank. For ten points, name this position that oversees American public health.", "answer": "<b> Surgeon General</b> of the United States", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One of these weapons was the source of General John Henry Parker\u2019s nickname. During the New York Draft Riots, one of these weapons was used to defend the New York Times by Henry Raymond. These guns were used in the Emu War, and they were made by companies like Lewis and Vickers. In World War One, synchronization gears were included on aircraft so that these guns could fire through propellers. The use of these guns in \u201cnests\u201d and trenches killed soldiers in No Man\u2019s Land. For ten points, Hiram Maxim and John Gatling invented what type of fast-firing gun?", "answer": "<b> Machine</b> Guns (accept<b> Gatling</b> Gun or<b> Maxim</b> machine gun before they are mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "With Hugh Meredith, this man founded a publication that published a political cartoon created by this man showing a snake cut into eight parts above the words \u201cJoin, or Die.\u201d This man established the first library in all of America and the first fire department in a city where he also established an Ivy League institution in 1765. The editor of the<em> Pennsylvania Gazette</em>, for ten points, name this Founding Father sometimes called \u201cThe First American.\u201d", "answer": "Benjamin<b> Franklin</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Some of this country\u2019s most famous writers include Chinua Achebe [shin-wa UH-sheh-bay] and Wole Soyinka, and a civil war broke out in this country when the region of Biafra attempted to secede. President Goodluck Jonathan of this country was heavily criticised for his failure to prevent the 2014 kidnapping of the Chibok girls, and it has suffered many terrorist attacks from Boko Haram. For ten points, name this African country with its capital at Lagos.", "answer": "<b> Nigeria</b> Page 1", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man deployed the Blue Division to fight in Russia and created the National Movement as part of a corporatist state. In the Ifni War this man lost territory in the Sahara to Morocco, although he refused to cede Ceuta and Melilla. He chose Juan Carlos I as his successor and avoided joining Hitler during World War Two, averting war with Britain by not attacking Gibraltar. For ten points, name this Generalissimo and longtime dictator of Spain.", "answer": "Francisco<b> Franco</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "An organization at this site was inspired by Henry Wisner to create a \u201cGreat Chain\u201d designed by the Sterling Iron Works to impede enemy ships. That organization at this location later began a tradition of training \u201cthe Long Grey Line.\u201d Polish engineer Tadeusz Kosciuszko designed this site, the oldest continually held military garrison in the country. Benedict Arnold attempted to surrender this site to the British. For ten points, name this New York site where the United States Military Academy is located.", "answer": "<b> West Point</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "What is this trophy called?", "answer": "<b> Heisman</b> Memorial Trophy", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "John the Blind of Bohemia fought in this war whose first naval engagement took place at Sluys [slois], and Edward the Black Prince\u2019s reputation grew after his success at Najera in this conflict. The Treaty of Bretigny briefly halted this conflict that was depicted in Auguste Rodin\u2019s<em> The Burghers of Calais</em>. The battle of Crecy during this conflict demonstrated the power of the longbow, as did the battle of Agincourt. For ten points, the siege of Orleans was lifted by Joan of Arc in what lengthy conflict between England and France?", "answer": "<b> Hundred Years\u2019 War</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A 22-bar recurring theme in this work was inspired by a song from Franz Lehar\u2019s<em> The Merry Widow</em>. The Bolshoi Theatre Orchestra ended up premiering this piece in place of the intended city\u2019s orchestra, because the musicians in the latter were either starving or fighting. Known for its \u201cinvasion\u201d theme, this piece was supposedly dedicated to a place \u201cthat Stalin destroyed and Hitler merely finished off.\u201d For ten points, name this Dmitri Shostakovich symphony nicknamed for a Russian city that faced a siege during World War II.", "answer": "<b> Leningrad</b> Symphony (accept Symphony<b> Number 7</b>, in C major, Opus 60)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "One leader of this country issued Decree 88A, and that man overthrew the regime of William Tolbert, the final leader of the True Whig Party. Another leader of this country, Joshua Blahyri, believed himself to be invincible to bullets, and was thus known as General Buck Naked. In 2006, this nation elected Africa\u2019s first female head of state, Ellen Johnson Sirleaf, and another president was sentenced to 50 years in prison for war crimes involving blood diamonds. For ten points, name this country formerly led by Charles Taylor with capital Monrovia.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Liberia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Individuals who manufactured these objects went on strike in London in the 1880s due to increasing cases of \u201cphossy jaw\u201d caused by the white phosphorus used on these objects. Samuel Jones popularized Lucifers, a type of these objects that relies on friction, and Gustaf Pasch developed the \u201csafety\u201d version of these objects to prevent unintentional combustion. Hans Christian Andersen wrote a fairy tale about a young girl selling, for ten points, these objects that produce a flame when a piece of wood or paper including a flammable substance is struck against a rough surface.", "answer": "<b> Match</b>sticks", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "The case<em> Aronow v. United States</em> was brought about due to Aronow\u2019s belief that one of this phrase\u2019s uses was \u201crepugnant to the Establishment Clause.\u201d A request from Mark Watkinson convinced Salmon P. Chase to first use this phrase in its most identifiable capacity, an idea perhaps first put forth in the fourth stanza of \u201cThe Star-Spangled Banner.\u201d An Eisenhower-era resolution resulted in this phrase officially replacing<em> E pluribus unum</em> as the motto of the United States. For ten points, name this religiously themed four-word phrase appearing on all U.S. currency.", "answer": "<b> In God We Trust</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man\u2019s wife, Rachel Donelson, was the subject of accusations of bigamy during one brutal political campaign. As part of his \u201cwar\u201d with Nicholas Biddle, this politician selected\u201cpet (+) banks\u201d to receive additional federal funding. His support for the Indian Removal Act led to the resettlement of the Cherokee Nation, and his loss in the \u201ccorrupt bargain\u201d of (*)</b> 1824 ushered in his successful run in 1828. For ten points, name this man, a Tennessee congressman, hero of the War of 1812, and Democratic president.", "answer": "Andrew<b> Jackson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Under this man, the purchase of officer ranks was abolished in the Cardwell Reforms.</b> <b>This man launched one of the first modern political campaigns in the (+)</b> <b>Midlothian</b> <b>Campaign but was less successful working with Charles Parnell in securing Irish home rule. This man\u2019s popularity declined after the death of Charlie Gordon in the Sudan, while this man\u2019s (*)</b> conservative rival was preferred by Queen Victoria. For ten points, name this Liberal prime minister of the United Kingdom.", "answer": "William Ewart<b> Gladstone</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A house belonging to a freed black man named Abraham Brian was occupied by one side during this battle. Lewis Armistead died from wounds obtained while leading troops to an area known as the \u201cHigh-water Mark of\u201d one side during this battle, which was the farthest</b> <b>point up (+)</b> <b>Cemetery Ridge that the attackers reached. James Longstreet vehemently</b> <b>opposed an event at this battle which resulted in a casualty rate of over 50% for the (*) </b>Confederacy. Pickett\u2019s Charge occurred during, for ten points, what 1863 Civil War battle fought around a Pennsylvania town.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Gettysburg</b>  (1) <b>A member of this military unit nicknamed \u201cIndian\u201d went on to found a mill</b> <b>beyond the Genesee River and became one of the first people to develop Rochester. 100 members of this group helped capture Fort Crown Point under the leadership</b> <b>of Seth Warner, who also led this group at the Battle of (+)</b> <b>Bennington. Henry</b> <b>Knox led an expedition to retrieve guns from Fort Ticonderoga after it had been captured with the help of this group. Members of this group tried to obtain the New Hampshire grants to (*)</b> establish what became the fourteenth state. For ten points, name this Vermont-based military group organized by Ethan Allen. ANSWER:<b> Green Mountain Boys</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}